mybigcampus.com 2013-06-01

# My Big Campus Privacy Policy

The following privacy policy applies to personal data collected at [www.lightspeedsystems.com](http://www.lightspeedsystems.com/) , [www.mybigcampus.com](http://www.mybigcampus.com/) , or [www.mybigcampus.co.uk](http://www.mybigcampus.co.uk/) . Lightspeed Systems Inc. and its affiliates (collectively "Lightspeed Systems") are committed to the security and protecting the privacy of its users. Because Lightspeed Systems gathers certain types of information about the users of the Services, we believe you should fully understand the terms and conditions surrounding the use of the information we collect. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the Services.  If you are using any of the Services through an educational or other institution that is a customer of Lightspeed Systems, this policy does not supersede the terms of any agreements between Lightspeed Systems and any other party, nor does it affect the terms of any agreement between any user of the Services and their employer, their educational institution or any third party.  Please make sure that you read the terms of any privacy policies that you enter into with parties other than Lightspeed Systems, including your employer or educational institution, as those policies may also explain how your personal information is used by those parties. If you are accessing Lightspeed through a third-party, public or unsecured internet provider, please be advised that any information you disclose or publish during the course of such access may be collected by any such provider and that Lightspeed Systems has no control and makes no representation as to the possible use of this information by any such provider. 

Please review the following statement to understand how the information you provide to Lightspeed Systems through the Services will be treated.

* **Information Lightspeed Systems collects.**

It is Lightspeed Systems' policy to limit the collection of personal information from children to only that which is necessary to utilize Lightspeed Systems products and services. Parents should consult the school's Acceptable Use, Social Media, Personnel and Instructional Policies for more information about the school's policies and practices for protecting children on the Internet. Teachers are reminded to also be aware of their obligations under the Ethical Standards for educators in their state, and to be conscious of their role as a model for students while interacting with students while using Lightspeed Systems products and services.

**For all Lightspeed Systems products and services (e.g., MyBigCampus):** we may collect the following types of personally identifiable information directly from children: first name; last name; email address; mobile phone number and carrier (optional for notifications); password; IP address; grade level; and school. We may also generate a login ID for the child that is different than the child's actual name. 

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information:** We may collect certain non-personally identifiable information from visitors to our site, such as the date and time of their visit, the type of browser used (e.g., Chrome, Firefox, Internet Explorer), the type of operating system used (e.g., Windows 7 or Mac OS), the ISP from which the visitor receives Internet access, and aggregate information regarding what pages users of the site access or visit. 

We may also collect non-personally identifiable information from registered members and match it to personally identifiable information (such as the member's name) in our database. Such combined information is kept in our internal database under the member's user name.

Lightspeed Systems gathers information about all users collectively, such as what areas users visit most frequently and what services users access most often. Lightspeed Systems automatically logs IP addresses, session sources, and other data which tracks users' access to the Services. We analyze these logs for sales and marketing purposes as well as system performance monitoring. These logs are analyzed for the aggregate trends they reveal about our customers and how the customers use the Services, not for the behaviors of individual users.

* **Student Safety**

Lightspeed Systems, makers of My Big Campus, complies with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA, see www.ftc.gov/privacy/coppafaqs ) to insure the online safety of children. Student accounts on My Big Campus are provided only through a verified educator, school, or educational organization. Educators should obtain parental permission before issuing accounts to students. 

We meet the following guidelines listed below and agree to:

  * NOT collect online contact information without the consent of either a parent or a qualified educator or educational institution. Without prior parental consent, online information will only be used to respond directly to the child's request and will not be used for other purposes
  * NOT collect personally identifiable offline contact information without prior parental consent
  * NOT distribute to third parties any personally identifiable information without prior parental consent
  * NOT entice by the prospect of a special game, prize or other activity or to divulge more information than is needed to participate in the activity

* **Purposes of Data Collection**

Lightspeed Systems requests personal information for purposes such as the provision of customer service and support, billing, network management, customer surveys, sales management, support, newsletter subscriptions, user group memberships, event registration and sponsorship, offers of related services, and other exchanges of information.

* **What Lightspeed Systems does with the information it collects.**

Lightspeed Systems makes announcements, email, chat, forums, discussions, and/or news groups available in certain areas of the Services. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information, and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose any of your personal or other information in these or any other publicly available site. And if you see inappropriate content posted by any other user, please report that information to us so we can review the post and respond accordingly.

The personal information you supply to Lightspeed Systems will not be given, sold, rented, loaned, or otherwise disclosed to any third parties outside of Lightspeed Systems and its agents, except when we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to (i) comply with legal process, (ii) enforce the Terms of Use, (iii) respond to claims that any content provided by using the Services violates the rights of third parties, or (iv) protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Lightspeed Systems, its users, or the public. We do not use personal information for any other commercial purpose.

Lightspeed Systems may use aggregated personal information to determine the demographic composition of our user base and to distribute statistics and general marketplace information about Lightspeed Systems. This aggregate information does not identify specific users.

Certain non-personal information regarding users is recorded by the standard operation of the Internet servers hosting the Services. This information is primarily used to provide users of the Services with an enhanced online experience. Lightspeed Systems may disclose aggregated user statistics in order to describe the Services to prospective partners and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes.

* **User Options -- Opt-Out**

Users may opt out of receiving future promotional electronic mailings from Lightspeed Systems by following the unsubscribe procedures indicated in the mailing.  Individual end users of Lightspeed Systems software should contact their educational institution or other organization hosting the software for questions about access to the personal information collected by that institution.  Please contact us at the address below if you have any other questions or concerns about the information you receive from us or the information that we collect from you.

* **Access to Your Information**

Lightspeed Systems offers users the ability to correct or change the information collected during registration. Users may change this information at any time and as often as necessary by choosing the "edit account information" option or other similar functionality offered in the Services.  To access or change your personal information, log in to your account through the Services.  For data not available through such an account, please contact us at the address listed below.

* **Security**

All of your personal information is stored on servers at locations designed specifically to ensure that no unauthorized individuals have access to the server or its data. 

* **European Union Data Protection**

If you reside in the European Union, upon registration you will be indicating your explicit consent that the personal information you have provided may be transferred and stored in countries outside the EU, including the United States. If you fail to provide your consent, you will not be permitted to access the Services for which registration is required. Lightspeed Systems adheres to the U.S. Safe Harbor Privacy framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union and is registered with the [U.S. Department of Commerce’s Safe Harbor Program](http://export.gov/safeharbor) . 

In order to comply with the European Union’s Safe Harbor Principles, Lightspeed Systems commits to the resolution of complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information.  We have committed to resolve any complaints by European Union citizens relating to this policy, which cannot be resolved directly with our company, through the EU Safe Harbor Dispute Resolution Procedure administered by the Council of Better Business Bureaus, Inc.

If you have any questions regarding this policy, please contact: 

John Genter   
Lightspeed Systems Inc.   
1800 19th Street   
Bakersfield, CA 93301   
Phone: 661.716.7600 

* **Lightspeed Systems Privacy Policy Statement Changes**

If Lightspeed Systems changes this privacy statement, we will post those changes at <http://www.lightspeedsystems.com/about/PrivacyPolicy.aspx> so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and whether we will disclose it to anyone. By using the Services, you signify your assent to the Lightspeed Systems Privacy Policy Statement, including any updates or changes to this policy. If you do not agree to this statement, please do not use the Services. Your continued use of the Services following the posting of changes to these terms will be interpreted by Lightspeed to signify your acceptance of those changes and will be relied upon by us for that purpose. 

* **Contact Lightspeed Systems**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the information that we collect from you, or the Services, please contact us at [privacy@lightspeedsystems.com](mailto:privacy@lightspeedsystems.com) or write to: 

Legal Department   
Lightspeed Systems Inc.   
1800 19th Street   
Bakersfield, CA 93301 

In the event that you are concerned about how data you have provided Lightspeed Systems through the Services has been used, please contact us at one of the addresses listed above. Lightspeed Systems takes all concerns about privacy and use of data very seriously, and shall endeavor to reply to you within two business days to commence its investigation of your concerns. 

We self-certify compliance with
